# João Santos

**Full-Stack Developer** 

#### **Personal Info**



+39 34 55 29 89 55



j-almeidasantos@hotmail.com



j-almeidasantos



jsantos42



j-almeidasantos.engineer



Bari, IT

#### Languages

Portuguese	C2
English	C2
French	B2
Italian	B2
Spanish	B1

#### **Tech Stack**









express **NEXT**...s



















As a **medical doctor** with **6+ years of clinical practice**, I became frustrated with the **poorly designed software** we were forced to use daily. I knew the UX/UI could be dramatically improved with more intuitive, user-friendly designs. This led me to **pivot my career** and become a full-stack developer, so that I **could be part of the solution**.

With my clinical background and passion for programming, I have the perfect blend of skills to build software that truly meets the needs of medical professionals.

My ultimate dream: help revolutionise the UX of healthcare software.

## **Experience**

Oct 2022 - present

## **Full Stack Developer (remote)**

haelsi (Vienna)

- Leveraging my background as a doctor to develop a user-centric  $\ensuremath{\mathbf{EMR}}$  software
- Collaborating with a cross-functional team in a **full remote** work environment
- Maintaining and enhancing an existing web application, using **Ember.js** on the frontend and **Laravel (PHP)** on the backend
- Containerising the existent web application to create a staging environment
- Conducting comprehensive testing (QUnit and PHPUnit) and debugging
- Utilising  ${\bf Python}$  for creating scripts and automation tools and streamlining manual tasks
- Conducting thorough code reviews, debugging, and bug fixing
- Working in an **agile** environment, including daily stand-ups, sprint planning, and retrospectives, to ensure timely project delivery
- Collaborating with stakeholders and end users, to gather feedback and implement new features

Jan 2022 - Jun 2022

### **Software Engineer Intern**

Critical Techworks (Lisbon)

- Working on the **frontend** of BMW's cars' infotainment, developing the Human Machine Interface (**HMI**) of the Navigation panel
- Maintaining the existing codebase (in C++)
- Adding new features and making Unit Tests
- Adding new UI with the QT framework

Jun 2020 - Dec 2021

#### **Graduate Student Researcher**

Universidade de Lisboa

The thesis of my Master degree in Clinical Nutrition involved:

- Geospatial data analysis using Python and R
- Making use of Jupiter notebook and geopandas

Oct 2014 - Jul 2021

#### **Medical Doctor**

ARSLVT (Lisbon), APHP (Paris)

- Medical student and resident "externe" in Paris (Oct 2014 Jul 2016)
- Clerkship in Uppsala (Jul 2015)
- GP resident in **Lisbon** + working shifts in the **ER department** of the largest hospital in the country (Mar 2018 Jul 2021)

## **Education**

Oct 2020

**Software Engineering Course** 

- Oct 2022

42 Lisboa

Sep 2018 - Dec 2021 Master's Degree in Clinical Nutrition

Universidade de Lisboa

Sep 2010 - Jul 2016 **Doctor of Medicine** 

Universidade de Lisboa & Pierre et Marie Curie Université

#### **Hobbies**

Cycling Hiking Cooking Reading Learning Traveling Sailing